Native American Women's Health Education Resource Center Records, 1986-2011
Sophia Smith Collection
- SERIES IX. STUDIES AND REPORTS
  - Dakota Round Table reports, [see SERIES VI. ORGANIZATION FILES]
    - "ESF [Eagle Staff Fund] $62,032 Start-Up Grants Case Study Report" by Pame Kingfisher, Apr 1988 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Focus Group Examining the Indian Health Service's Reproductive Health Care for Native American Women in the Aberdeen Area (Box 20)
      - Report # 1, "The Current Status of Indian Health Service's Reproductive Health Care" 1999 (Box 20, Folder 9)
      - Report #2, "Young Native American Women's Knowledge of Reproductive Tract Infections" 1999 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - "Health Survey for the Yankton Sioux Reservation Community," Leslie Boyd, Nov 1993 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - "The Impact of Norplant in the Native American Community"
      - Report by Natasha Lowry and Charon Asetoyer, Jun 1992 (Box 20, Folder 12)
      - Drafts and correspondence 1991-92 (Box 20, Folder 13)
      - Interviews, spring 1992 (Box 20, Folder 14)
      - Norplant Project interviews, Tiya Miles, fall 1992 (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - "Indigenous Women's Reproductive Rights/Justice" series
      - "The Indian Health Service and Its Inconsistent Application of the Hyde Amendment," by Kati Schindler, Anna E. Jackson, and Charon Asetoyer, Oct 2002 (Box 21)
        - Report (Box 21, Folder 1)
        - Mailing lists for distribution of paper (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - "Roundtable Report on Access to Abortion Services Through the Indian Health Service Under the Hyde Amendment," Apr 2003 (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - "A Survey of Sexual Assault Policies and Protocols Within Indian Health Service Emergency Rooms," by Julie Andrews, Bryony Heise, and Charon Asetoyer, Jan 2005 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Maternal Health and Pre-Natal Care report draft, undated (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - "The Positive Impact of Community Based Self-Help Education Among the Native American Diabetic Population of the Yankton Sioux Reservation," Sonya Shin, 1991
      - Report (Box 21, Folder 6)
      - Drafts and notes (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - "Radon in My Community: The Impact of Radon In the Yankton Sioux Communities," Michele Dickson, 1992
      - Report (Box 21, Folder 8-9)
      - Drafts and notes (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - "Recycling or Alleged Recycling? A Review of the Hydromex Waste Processing System," Heather Gilbert 1994 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - "Report on and Analysis of the Yankton Sioux Reservation Community Health Fairs: Winter 1993-94," Linda Appel, 1994 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - "A Report on Southern Missouri Waste Management Association's Proposed Landfill Project in the Lake Andes Area, South Dakota," Sia Lindstrom 1993 (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - "Report on the Southern Missouri Recycling and Waste Management District's Operations," Patricia Bachmann, 12 Mar 1998 (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - "Revictimizing the Battered: An Investigation of the Charles Mix County Criminal Justice System's Management of Domestic Violence Cases," Halle Liza Gafori 1994 (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - "A Review of the Use and Effects of Depo-Provera on Native American Women"by Ellen Chen and Charon Asetoyer, summer 1995 (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - "A Study of the Herbicide and Pesticide Use Within the Lake Andes Watershed on the Yankton Sioux Reservation," Susie Lim 1996 (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - "A Study of the Use of Depo-Provera and Norplant by the Indian Health Services"
      - Report and revised report by Lin Krust and Charon Asetoyer, Jul 1993 (Box 21, Folder 18)
      - Questionnaires, Naomi Sunshine, spring 1993 (Box 21, Folder 19)
      - Protocol notes 1993 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - "A Survey of the Indian Health Service Abortion Policy and Its Application by Indian Health Service Units," by Kati Schindler, Jul 2002 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - "Wakanhejah (They Too Are Sacred): Federal Funding, the Current Education State, and Achieving Academic Excellence for All Children in Lake Andes," Jennifer Wies & Charon Asetoyer 2000 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Yankton Sioux Health Report draft (Amy) 1994 (Box 22, Folder 4)
- SERIES X. SUBJECT FILES
  - Abortion 1990-91, undated (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Adolescent health 1991, undated (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - AIDS
    - Native Americans 1989-96 (Box 22, Folder 7-8)
    - Training for Cultural Competence in the HIV Epidemic 1992-93 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Women 1987-96 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Alcohol and drug dependency
    - General 1985-97 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Cocaine babies 1988-91 (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Fetal alcohol syndrome 1981-92 (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Inhalants 1991, undated (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Birth Control
    - General 1987-95, undated (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Norplant 1990-95, undated (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Body composition measurement 1993-94, undated (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Cancer
    - General 1994-96, undated (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Breast cancer 1990-96, undated (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Child welfare and abuse 1989-95 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Children's health 1979, undated (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Children's rights 1984 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Cholesterol 1989-93, undated (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Colleges and universities 1985, undated (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Diabetes and nutrition 1983-98, undated (Box 23, Folder 9-11)
  - Diarrhea-Oral rehydration therapy 1979-91, undated (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Domestic violence and sexual assault
    - General 1985-99, undated (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - South Dakota Victim Services Directory 1985-99, undated (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - Support group materials 1985-97, undated (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - Training 1997, undated (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Elderly 1996-98, undated (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Electro-magnetic fields, undated (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - Environment/Environmental Justice
    - General 1990-2004 (Box 23, Folder 19)
    - General (cont'd) 1990-2004 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Contaminants and reproductive health 1980-93 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Hepatitis vaccine experiment, Pine Ridge Indian Reservation 1990 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Housing and homelessness 1987-92 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Indian News, Bureau of Indian Affairs newsletter 1991-93 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Lead exposure, occupational 1997-98 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Native American
    - Culture and issues (Box 24)
      - General 1981-96, undated (Box 24, Folder 7-10)
      - Boarding school interviews 1998 (Box 24, Folder 11)
      - Casinos 1984-92 (Box 24, Folder 12)
      - Dakota culture: Seven Council Fires, undated (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - Education 1991-95 (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - Health (Box 24)
      - General 1989-97 (Box 24, Folder 15)
      - Treatment programs 1998, undated (Box 24, Folder 16)
      - Tribal health resources (Box 24)
        - Nebraska, undated (Box 24, Folder 17)
        - South Dakota (Box 24)
          - General 1993, undated (Box 24, Folder 18)
          - Cheyenne River Sioux Tribe, undated (Box 24, Folder 19)
          - Crow Creek Sioux Tribe 1989 (Box 24, Folder 20)
      - World Health Organization Participatory Research Management Guidelines: draft 2002 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Resources/Organizations 1986-98 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Nuclear waste 1994-97, undated (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Racism 1988-96, undated (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Reproductive health
    - General 1988-98 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Catholic Church 1994-98, undated (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Childbirth picture book, undated (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Reproductive rights 1984-92, undated (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Rural health issues 1989 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Self-help OB/GYN 1979-94, undated (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Sexually transmitted diseases 1984-96, undated (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Smoking 1990 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Sterilization 1994-2000, undated (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - South Dakota voting rights 2006 (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Teen pregnancy prevention 1997, undated (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Teen suicide, undated (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - Temporary Assistance for Needy Families (TANF) 1997, undated (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - Traditional healing 1988 (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - Women of color and health 1990-98, undated (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Women's health 1991-95, undated (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous 1994, undated (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - HoHHH (Box 26)
- SERIES XI. YANKTON SIOUX TRIBE (YST)
  - General and History
    - General 1982-2000, undated (Box 26, Folder 4-5)
    - Gravesite near White Swan 1991-92 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Sioux history 1934-94, undated (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Yankton Sioux history 1967-96, undated (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Domestic Abuse Code, undated (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Domestic Violence Probation Officer, undated (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - First American Footwear Corporation 1992 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Fort Randall Casino 1991-92 (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Healthy Start Program 1990-93, undated (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - "Jurisidiction Case" Yankton Sioux Tribe v. Gaffey
    - General 1998-2004 (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - Memorandum Opinion and Order 1998 (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - Appeal 1999 (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - Landfill, [see also SERIES IX. STUDIES AND REPORTS]
    - General 1991-97, undated (Box 26, Folder 17)
    - Fact sheets and newspaper clippings 1993-95, undated (Box 26, Folder 18)
    - Environmental Protection Agency (Box 26)
      - General 1995-96 (Box 26, Folder 19)
      - "EPA Hearings, Lake Andes Proposed Landfill 1/24/96" by Charon Asetoyer (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Legal (Box 27)
      - South Dakota v. Greger: Appeal 1997 (Box 27, Folder 2)
      - South Dakota v. Yankton Sioux Tribe reports on decision, Jan 1998 (Box 27, Folder 3)
      - Yankton Sioux Tribe v. Southern Missouri Solid Waste (Box 27, Folder 4)
      - Management District and Southern Missouri Solid Waste (Box 27)
      - Management District v. State of South Dakota 1995-96 (Box 27)
    - Reference file on landfills 1993-97, undated (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Reference file on watersheds 1992-96, undated (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Southern Missouri Solid Waste Management Association (Box 27)
      - General 1997-98 (Box 27, Folder 7)
      - Grant applications 1994 (Box 27, Folder 8)
      - Permit application 1993 (Box 27, Folder 9)
      - Revised permit 1996 (Box 27, Folder 10)
      - Site Characterization Study for Solid Waste Landfill, Jan and Jul 1993 (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Veterans Administration/Housing and Urban Development Appropriations bill 1997-98 (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Voices Organized to Save the Environment (VOTE) (Box 27)
      - General 1993-94, undated (Box 27, Folder 13)
      - "Report on Southern Missouri Waste Management Association's Proposed Landfill Project" by Sia Lindstrom, Jun 1993 (Box 27, Folder 14)
      - Appellant's Reply Brief in the matter of the Proposed Municipal Solid Waste Permit to Southern Missouri Solid Waste Management, Inc., 10 May 1994 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Law enforcement
    - Lake Andes police/jail issues and boycott 1989-2004, undated (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Charles Mix County Jail conditions 2003-04 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Marina (proposed) at Fort Randall dam 1993 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Northern Plains Native Nations Treaty Council meeting 1996 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Operation Eagle 1983 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Pesticides Code, undated (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Potential funding sources 1996, undated (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Recycling Curriculum, circa 1997 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - "Redistricting Case" Blackmoon et al v. Charles Mix County
    - General 2005 (Box 28, Folder 10-11)
    - Ward II 2001-05 (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - Andes Central School District boundaries 2005 (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - "Remains Case" Yankton Sioux Tribe v. Corps of Engineers 1999-2000 (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - Schools
    - General 1988-91, undated (Box 28, Folder 15)
    - Marty Indian School (Box 28)
      - Infirmary 1989-90 (Box 28, Folder 16)
      - Grant application, "Seventh Generation Council Striving for Sobriety by the Year 2000," 1990 (Box 28, Folder 17)
      - Lead poisoning 1996-97 (Box 28, Folder 18)
      - Fly-ash report 1997 (Box 28, Folder 19)
  - South Dakota Equal Justice Commission 2005 (Box 28, Folder 21)
  - Teton Sioux Nation Treaty Council Report (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Tribal Youth Program 2001 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - United Sioux Tribes of South Dakota Development Corporation
    - Energy Transportation Systems, Inc. 1981 (Box 29, Folder 3-4)
    - Pick-Sloan Power 1981-82 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Threat Package 1982 (Box 29, Folder 6)
- SERIES XII. RESTRICTED MATERIALS
  - Interns 1990-95, 2005 (Box 30, Folder 1-5)
    [CLOSED UNTIL JANUARY 1, 2037]
  - Staff evaluations - (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Computer disks containing slide presentations and reports 1992-2005 (Box 30, Folder 7)
    [Original audiovisual materials are closed to research. Researchers interested in accessing audiovisual materials for which there is no extant use copy should contact the Sophia Smith Collection to discuss options]
- OVERSIZE MATERIALS
  - City of Lake Andes zoning map, 1984; and posters and newsletters 1993-2005, undated two AIDS prevention posters from Cameroon, n.d. (Map-case Flat File)
  - Conference [unidentified] planning flip chart sheets, undated (Map-case Flat File)
  - Newspapers: miscellaneous issues of Apache Scout, Dakota Journal, Indian Country Today, Lakota Eyapaha/Sicangu Sun Times, Lakota Journal, Lakota Times, Morena Newspaper, Native Voice, Sioux Messenger, Wagner Post 1989-2005 (Map-case Flat File)
  - Flip chart sheets "For Future Discussion"undated (Map-case Drawer 49)